CYRIL GARCIA

CONTACT

Phone:

408-440-6918

Email:

garciacy@bycyril.com

Website:

bycyril.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/garciacy

GitHub:

github.com/cyrilivargarcia

SKILLS

Skills

- Swift
- Objective-C
- Java
- Python
- Javascript

Development

- iOS and Web Dev
- IBM Watson
- Google Firebase
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning

Background

I am an incoming graduate at Evergreen Valley College by Spring 2018, with an Associates Degree in Mathematics. I will be continuing my education at San Jose State University by Fall 2018 to major in Statistics and Computer Science and pursue a career in Software Engineering.

I enjoy developing software for both mobile and web while learning about Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Artificial Intelligence. I've gained my experience through relevant education, internships, and personal projects; many of which can be accessed through my website or my GitHub.

Experience

Code Coach, the Coder School July 2017 - present

Teaching basic programming to iOS Development.

LinkedIn High School Mentorship Program, LinkedIn, March 2015 - May 2015

• Learned the basics of HTML and CSS from Linkedln Web Developers.

iOS Developer Intern, ESUHSD, — June 2015 - December 2016

Developed the East Side Union High School District App.

Education

San Jose State University, San Jose, CA — BS, Statistics and Computer Science, 2018 - 2021 Evergreen Valley College, San Jose, CA — AS, Mathematics, 2015 - 2018

Projects

GeekWeather (iOS)

Elegant weather app for iOS; displaying my proficiency in iOS Development and UI/UX Design.

FileStorks.com (web)

An easy file sharing solution.

SwiftyCoreData (iOS open source)

• A library to make is easier for developers to implement CoreData.

Spinners (iOS open source)

A library for dynamic activity indicators.

SnakeAl (mini web project)

Simple snake game with Al